How did General MacArthur become the
dictator of Japan? After World War II,
the plan was for an Allied Council to
rule the country. But its new Supreme
Commander, Douglas MacArthur, shut them
all out and took total control. For the
next 6 years, he wasn't a general. He
was a dictator. He single-handedly
disarmed millions of Japanese soldiers.
He forced Japan to accept a new
democratic constitution, one that his
American staff had written in a single
week. He shattered the power of the
ancient aristocratic families and giant
corporations that had fueled the war and
gave Japanese women the right to vote.
MacArthur was Japan's new shogun, a
military dictator who single-handedly
destroyed the old Japan and built a new
one from the ground